[Music]
You see how believers do a lot of
foolish things sometimes?
Decisions.
Decisions. Question. Have you chosen to
succeed or do you just desire it? Have
you chosen to be a very godly person or
do you just desire it? Have you chosen
to not be a failure
or do you just hate failure? I hope you
know hating failure is different from
choosing to be a success. You can hate
failure. You can detest it honestly and
yet you find out that your life becomes
a perpetual you know a a road map of a
failure. Hating it is not enough. You
must make that choice. your decisions.
Hallelujah.
Let me tell you three ways. Three ways
to make superior choices. Write that
quickly. Three ways.
Three ways
to make superior choices. Are you ready?
Number one,
in order to make superior choices, the
first thing you need is an awareness.
Listen, an awareness of the word of God.
What the word of God says, promises, a
vast, you need an awareness of the word
of God. I'm going to read it for you,
but I just want you to get the idea. An
awareness of what the word of God says.
Access to wisdom by the word. That's how
I wrote it there. You need access to
wisdom by the word.
An awareness
of what the word of God proposes for
you. Else you cannot make quality
choices.
Access to wisdom by the word of God.
Is someone writing?
That's the first thing you need. an
awareness of what is there for you. I
call them exceeding great and precious
promises. If you don't know the superior
alternative God has given you, you will
you will dance to everything around you.
Do you know for instance that God has
exalted you? Do you know for instance
that God has a destiny of beauty and
glory for you? Jeremiah 29:11. Do you
know that the Bible says the path of the
just is as a shining light that shineth
more and more unto the perfect day? Do
you know according to scripture that
though your beginning be small that your
latter end should greatly increase? Do
you know that you have been called out
of every tribe and every tongue and
every nation that the limitations from
your territory don't have to become your
limitations again? Do you know that you
can come boldly to the throne of grace
that you may obtain mercy and grace,
find grace to help in time of need? Do
you know
if you don't have knowledge, you cannot
make superior decisions?
Wisdom, access to wisdom by the word of
God is the first key if you want to make
superior decisions. And when I say
wisdom by the word of God, I'm not just
limiting it to scripture directly alone.
I'm also talking of access to knowledge
from word compliant materials. Maybe you
may want to write that down. Access to
wisdom first by the word of God and then
from word compliant materials. There are
books, there are tapes, there are
videos, there are teachings that are a
distilling of wisdom.
I was listening to
God's servant, Bishop David Oedico,
as he gave a rundown of the things he
had learned as he celebrated his 71st
birthday. And I mean it was an unveiling
of superior wisdom for me. As I was
listening, I was just thinking to myself
praying that everybody who was hearing
that great father of faith was actually
paying attention to the things he was
saying because you know sometimes you
can be around and just shout and say
amen and not be getting anything.
Priceless valuable lessons he had
learned at 71.
I received it with prayer.
Thank you for the leverage of granting
me access to a 71-year-old wisdom so
that by the time I am 71 I would have
doubled or tripled my progress.
Is someone learning now?
You cannot make a destiny
defining decision wallowing among
gossips and failures and small-minded
people and people who don't respect God.
They don't respect success. They don't
respect successful people. They downplay
on sacrifices. you any decision derived
from that mold will always be
sabotaging.
Is someone learning?
You have given me a destiny
and a purpose to fulfill.
So it all I am, every breath in me, I'll
spend my life to see.
You have given me a destiny
and a purpose to fulfill.
So with all I am, every breath in me,
I'll spend my life to see.
This song is a declaration of your power
to choose.
But it started by saying, "You have
given me. I am aware. I have found from
scripture."
Ephesians 1 and:3
that you've made all blessings
available for me, spiritual blessings in
heavenly places in Christ. And so I use
my will, my power to choose in
partnership with the word of God, in
partnership with word compliant
materials, in partnership with the Holy
Spirit to make proestiny choices.
Being prayerful is a proestiny choice.
Being disciplined is a proestiny choice.
Being godly is a proestiny choice. Are
we together? Being compassionate is a
proestiny choice. Being diligent,
hardworking, if you want to call it, is
a proestiny choice. Being persistent is
a proestiny choice. Learning given to
continuous learning, never plateauing in
life is a proestiny choice. Being lazy
is a destiny sabotaging choice. being
very loud when you have not arrived,
living a fake life, a false life. That
that's that's you fighting your destiny.
Hanging around people who are going
nowhere. I remind you of a statement
that I made that if there are five
foolish people around you, you didn't
count. Well, there are six people, you
are the sixth.
If there are five wise people around
you, you also didn't count well. There
are six, you will be in the six. You
will be a mess average of the people
around you. It's true.
You want greatness and you hang around
people who hate God, hate God's people,
hate victory, hate discipline, hate
knowledge, hate diligence. No sir, you
are not going anywhere. I don't have to
prophesy. You don't need any cause in
your life.
Show me a man, no matter how weak, that
has found himself through honor, to be
in proximity with them who love God,
them who are disciplined, them who are
going somewhere, not people who gossip
talking about people, minds that have
been refined by knowledge. When you hear
them speak, they speak of excellent
things. I show you someone who will
never remain small.
So the first key if you want to make
predestiny decisions is that you must
know how to have access to wisdom by the
word of God alongside word compliant
resources. You must know how to draw
wisdom from there.
Apostle, by the grace of God, I'm going
to be an exceptional father and husband.
I don't believe in you until I see what
you are reading. I don't believe that
statement. I know you are joking. Until
I see, show me who is shaping your
mindset on fatherhood. Show me who is
shaping your mindset on being a
responsible husband. Then I can know
whether your confession is blind or you
will be a repetition of where you are
coming from. Apostle, I'm going to be a
great woman. Esther Deborah stories. If
it's positive conversion, that's fine.
Show me who is shaping your mind. If
it's some frustrated person online
transferring her frustration to you. No
ma. No ma. No ma.
Apostle. By the grace of God, I'm going
to build churches. I will be so blessed.
I will love the Lord. I love your
sincerity, but I don't believe you. Show
me who you are learning from. Show me
who you are learning from. Let me see
the books you are reading that expose
you to diligence, to relationships, to
value, to the power of competence and
excellence.
Show me. Then I believe you. Ladies and
gentlemen, your decisions are as
superior as the materials that inform
your mindset. Your decisions are as
your mindset.
A man with a losers mentality cannot
make a winner's decision. No sir, a man
with a losers mentality, I repeat, no
matter how sincere, no matter how well
intentioned, a man, a woman, a pastor, a
businessman with a losers mentality,
losers mentality being a description,
not an insult, you cannot produce a
winner's decision. The cancer is from
within. That's where it must change.
Listen,
there are parents today, with all due
respect, when they see their children
going to church and being zealous about
the things of God, because they
themselves are not serious with God,
they think the children are doing too
much. What are you going to do in church
again? midweek prayer every time you are
in church is not the man's fault. He has
not prioritized God. So he cannot watch
his child have value beyond his level of
understanding. Are you seeing the
problem now? So he will retreat the
child back and then the child stays back
home now not doing anything and there's
the devil will come pornography and
because the boy is at home and he's idle
he's not doing anything and he has
access to an Android phone where he
would have been in church learning
growing building having a community of
kingdom-minded people because the father
with all due respect or the mother or
the parents every parent transfers to
their children their passion for God or
otherwise a Man that believes in fasting
and prayer, believes in diligent
spirituality, the word of God, will most
likely give the children the enabling
environment to replicate same. Am I
right on that? A man who does not place
value on God will tell the child, "Go
and make money." This church thing, and
before you know it, the child becomes a
failure.
You can't bless beyond your mindset.
You cannot bless beyond your mindset.
Even if you want to, you can't bless
beyond your mindset. Another example,
watch a father tell a child, "Be
hardworking. Don't be lazy. Be great."
That's not the key to greatness. But
that's all the man knows. That's all the
man knows. He wants his child to be
great. And unfortunately, he's not
accessed the word nor word compliant
materials to methodically walk that boy
through an enviable destiny. All he
knows that he heard is all he tells the
boy. Be great. Be serious. And the boy
will say, "I'm trying to." But
unfortunately, sometimes a man may be
too proud to not sit down and learn that
although you are sincere, this is not
the way greatness happens.
Coonia, I pray for you in Jesus name.
You will not enter something you hate
because of your decisions. You will not
hate a destiny and yet still enter into
it again in the name of Jesus Christ. As
God empowers your capacity to choose
tonight through this teaching, may you
begin to scale prophetic heights in the
name of Jesus Christ.
>> Hallelujah.
Blessed be the name of the Lord.
Decisions.
So you have two people for instance,
let's say real estate people. One
understands the law of diligence,
understands the law of relationships,
and understands the prophetic advantage.
I'm working with your mind, brother. A
real estate. He understands the law of
diligence. He's hardworking. He
understands the law of relationships,
strategic connections, and he
understands the prophetic advantage.
Brother Born again, he understands the
law of diligence, but does not
understand the law of relationships. So
even though he's a hardworking person,
network of architects and builders,
doors don't open because doors are
relational. They are more relational
than they are of skill. This man will
remain stunted. He doesn't know why his
inability to have learned that law has
become a a a stumbling block. Then the
guy does not understand the power of the
prophetic. Sometimes he even mocks it.
This guy will remain here. Whereas
somebody who sometimes may even be less
skilled than him is scaling height
because he's added other things and he's
making quality decisions. Are we
together now? When he gets a great
project,
ladies and gentlemen,
listen to me. If you do not understand
the mysteries of the kingdom, you will
not be able to make predestiny
decisions,
knowledge,
knowledge.
I'm thinking about my life and I'm
thinking about this ministry and I'm
thinking with all due respect of the
things that happen underground
that you may never see, you may never
know. but with all due respect are
responsible for the results you see and
admire. I can tell you one thing for
sure. Mastery nothing happens by
mistake. Did you hear what I said? Don't
just celebrate victories. Let it provoke
you to know how victories are
engineered.
How victories are engineered.
Someone asked me a question and he was
just celebrating what God did in giving
us the place he gave us. And he said,
"Apostle, how did you do it?" I told
him, I said, "I can't answer you because
it's not it's not a sentence.
Are we together?" The only way to answer
you is to walk you through a journey.
That's the answer. What am I going to
say now? If I say it is God, it's not a
lie. If I say diligence, it's not a lie.
If I say relationships, it's not a lie.
If I say mercy is not a lie. If I say
favor is not a lie. Which one do I omit
now in giving you the answer?
Nothing will change until your decisions
change.
The decision to leave bad friends
without insulting them and redefine a
new company whose values reflect where
you are going to is a superior decision.
That's your commitment.
Let me speak to a father. The decision
to take advantage of your home and be
the priest over your home, taking care
of your wife, taking care of your
children as unto God is a proestiny
decision. The decision to stop living
carelessly, traveling and leaving your
wife and children without knowing how
they are being taken care of and saying
it does not matter. And sometimes lots
of Christians are involved in this.
Let me speak to the women too. Madam,
you cannot leave your husband, no
cooking, your children, they are not and
you are busy doing whatever it is. Let
me tell you this is what I believe.
Anything that destroys your relationship
with Jesus, destroys your family,
destroys your health is not worth your
time. Did you hear what I said? Anything
that would destroy these three things,
your relationship with Jesus, your
family, and your health, believe me, is
not worth it.
It's not worth it. Because at the end of
it, these three things matter. If you
are not healthy, you will die. If your
family scatters into pieces, you will
see how depressing it will be for you.
They are the ones who will stay with you
when all the stakes are down. and then
ultimately your relationship with Jesus
decisions.
So number one, you must have access to
wisdom. Number two, the second way to
make strategic proestiny decisions is
that you must obtain grace from God.
Please listen, when you know what to do,
there is grace to do it. It's called the
doing grace. There are many people who
know what to do. They know the choices
to make but the engracing to make the
choices are not there. You obtain grace
from God to now actually make the
decisions.
You can make the decisions by writing
them down as a goal. You can make the
decisions in the place of prayer. But in
any case, the next step after you know
what to do is to obtain grace. I'll tell
you this ladies and gentlemen, any
decision that will reveal the glory of
God in your life must happen by the
grace of God. Are we together now? The
arm of flesh cannot make a decision that
glorifies God. The flesh of man
generally. So what you need is that when
you find the path you want to take, say
for instance, you are now making a
U-turn with your life and you are
leaving practices and things that are
not of God and you want to start on a
new leaf. Let me tell you, you don't
have the power. You can decide, but you
don't have the power. You can will to
do, but you must obtain grace from God.
Somebody say, I obtain grace.
>> Say it again. I obtain grace.
>> I obtain grace.
>> Please look at me. How many of you know
that many people who are prayerless know
the power of prayer? Why are they not
praying? How many of you know that even
an armed robber knows that a most
superior path to life is through dignity
and diligence? Am I right on that? Why
wouldn't he change?
Because it takes more than a desire. The
will to do it is there. But you need
empowerment. I'm praying for someone
sincerely because for some this is where
you are right now. It is not that you
don't know what to do. You know you
should read books. You know you should
be serious. You know you should wake up
in the morning and pray. You know that
you should fast. You know you should
bear roots downwards. But the power to
do it. Some of you know that you should
leave certain associations for good. But
the power
in the name of Jesus to all those
seeking that empowerment, the doing
grace. From the depth of my heart I pray
for you and for our family following
online. May the doing grace rest on you
now.
May the doing grace rest on you now.
May the grace to actually choose rest on
you now.
Do you know why I'm saying that?
Remember
sometimes when you choose it will come
with temporary constraints before you
now see the beauty. If grace is not
given you will not be persistent.
Are we together?
The person who decides for instance
and please don't feel bad decides to
stop living a man
who wants to give you money and destroy
your life and you make up your mind that
from today I will be a responsible lady
in all honesty and from a human
standpoint. You will suffer temporarily
because the meaning of that is that you
may go back to where you are coming
from. You will not get certain
privileges but it is a nobler decision
and sometimes the results will not show
immediately. So you will look like a
fool. Your other friends who you live in
the world they will look at you and say
look at your life. You were better off
now simply because this church thing has
hijacked you. You've taken away dignity
and you will feel stupid for a long
time.
So you need grace. You need grace.
Someone who used to drink and smoke and
live riotously. By the time you leave,
you will go through the period of
loneliness because those are the only
friends you have. Now, absorbing
yourself in church and learning all
this, you are entering a new lifestyle.
You need grace. Again, I pray for you in
the name of Jesus. The empowerment to
start making choices. Not just to know
what choices to make, but to actually
make those choices. I release that grace
on you now.
[Music]
My life must change.
>> My life must change.
>> I've touched your grace.
>> My mind must change. My mind must
change.
>> My mind must change.
>> I've touched your grace.
>> I
[Music]
Hallelujah.
I was looking at a few. Please sit down.
I was looking at a few of our photos
from
our conferences across the globe this
morning, I think it was.
And I sat very quietly as I was praying
and preparing for tonight.
I was almost in tears and all I was
saying is Lord mercy I thank you. I was
looking at the poster that you just saw
now looking at all the faces there and I
was thinking to myself the mercy of God.
But you know what the Holy Spirit
whispered back? He said the power of
choice.
It's not just mercy. the power of choice
because the same Lord is rich unto all
rainy season does not when rain falls it
doesn't just fall in one region it falls
everywhere so when you see someone's
bucket full of water the person also
took advantage and kept a bucket outside
you didn't want the rain to touch your
body so you stayed inside the
consequence is that it fell on the
ground and went away. But someone
brought buckets, the same rain that
would have filled your bucket. Are we
together? Someone used the opportunity.
Honestly, when I looked at everything,
all I was saying because you see
sometimes when you are in a position
like God has put me, you look at life in
a very different way.
When God gives you access to a
generation, honestly, sometimes all you
see is mercy.
mercy.
It is the grace and the mercy of God.
But while I meditated almost in tears
thanking God, the Holy Spirit whispered
it again to me. He said, "It is the
power of choice." The power of choice.
When the prayer grace came, some
received it, some rejected it. When the
diligence grace came, some received it,
some rejected it. When the persistence
grace came, some received it, some
rejected it. When the relational grace
came, some received it, some rejected
it. When the selflessness grace came,
some received it, some rejected it. When
the power grace came, some received it,
some rejected it. When the influence
grace came, some received it, some
rejected it.
Grace, grace, grace.
>> I see grace.
>> Grace, grace, grace. All
>> I see is grace.
>> Grace, grace, grace.
>> I see grace.
>> All I see is grace.
>> Everywhere that I go,
All I see is grace.
>> Hear me. Look at me. Paul said, "I am
what I am
by the grace of God." Give us that
scripture. He said, "But this grace,"
this is where I'm going to tonight. But
this grace, please find it for us media.
I am what I am by the grace of God. It
says, "And this grace that was bestowed
upon me was not in vain." It says, "But
I labored more abundantly than they
all." Are you reading that now? Give us
NIV. Let's see what NIV says.
By the grace of God, he says, "I am what
I am." It says, "And his grace to me was
not without effect. No, I worked harder
than all of them. Yet not I, but the
grace of God that was with me. So don't
you make a mistake in just singing about
the grace of God. Don't use it to
downplay the sacrifices. You take
advantage of the grace and then you walk
out your salvation in prayer. You walk
out your salvation in learning.
I just kept saying mercy. I flip through
the photos. the things that God did in
New York, the things that he did in
Glasgow, Scotland, the things that he
did in Calgary, and then earlier this
year in Dallas. I mean, mighty
manifestations of his power, the
healings, the miracles. I was just
watching from a third party view as
though I was not there. just looking at
the things that God did and looking at
the things that God is doing in this
ministry week in week out
an opportunity to speak to kings to
nobles and and I'm looking at it and say
God I just kept saying mercy mercy thank
you and the spirit of God whispered very
slowly to my heart it is the power of
choice
[Music]
sometimes because of our determination
to see Jesus glorified
We we hate trying to take credit for
anything and so we act as if we are
dummies and foolish in his presence. But
let me tell you the truth about it is
that even though the grace of God was
there, it took the stability and the
insistence of choice. I can tell you
moments when I was learning the law of
honor. I can tell you moments when I was
learning the law of favor. I can tell
you times of prayer and fasting. I don't
just give credit to these things. I can
tell you when you submit yourself to
learn where God grants you visions, the
visions of some of these things today.
You walk it out. You walk it out. You
walk it out. You walk it out. I remember
when I began to see the visions of the
nations. When God was revealing to me
that he would take me to the nations, I
looked at myself. I said, "The nations?"
Ah that means you need to contend for
light and power and wisdom. You need
finances. You need to learn the laws so
you don't manipulate people. Where will
you get that kind of money from?
[Music]
The grace to stand all the attacks that
come from the devil. The leadership and
organizational knowledge because it
takes more than anointing. It takes
leadership.
But you see, we are not the first doing
it. So we follow them while we look onto
Jesus. We follow them. Them who a lot of
people mock out of ignorance. Them who a
lot of people trivialize in spite of
their result. We have chosen the
foolishness of following as we look onto
Christ.
It is the grace of God. But there was
diligence.
Are we together now? Diligence.
Diligence.
times when anybody can give up, we
decided to continue and we pushed.
Ladies and gentlemen, let me tell you,
our generation has a cancer and praying
that God would deliver us from is the
cancer of trivializing the sacrifices of
people. You see, when you see people now
wear the royal apparel and they sit on
the throne, it covers the scars.
It does. It covers the scars. Are we
together? You look at my hand here. I
have a few scars. These scars came since
I was a small child. Regardless my
quality of life has refused to go. It's
just there. It reminds me of where I'm
coming from. I don't know. I can't even
remember how some of these cars came.
Whether it's play or hard work or life,
I I don't I can't remember.
Are we together? Scars.
But when I wear suit or I wear whatever
it is, you wouldn't see it. But don't be
mistaken. It's still there.
Ah there are people when you look at
their altar is blood you see dripping.
So while you are saying is the grace of
God make sure you don't trivialize it
that when others are sleeping they awake
are we together I once saw the photo of
a man beautiful photo he was trying to
protect his children and there were
arrows on his back but the children
could not see it. I said this is a
description of the destiny of many
people. The things they have received in
the spirit for others while shielding
them so that they will grow. Coonia body
of Christ hear me. We must return to the
place of not human worship but a
respectful and a healthy honor for the
sacrifices of people.
Hallelujah.
I can tell you this with all humility.
My beloved people, mastery is not by
mistake. I told you that when you see
consistency in results, even if the
people do not look like it, it is not a
mistake. It is engineered. It is
programmed. The thing about destiny is a
man will not look like it. But it does
not matter. It is the mindset, not the
form.
You can see a man very unassuming, but
they tell you he's a professor. Make no
mistakes about it. Till he tells you his
story, till he tells you all the things
he went through that he was reading when
he started he started reading with a
lantern all of that and he would tell
you the stories. We we we have a an
interesting way of trivializing the
sacrifices of people. I don't just mean
worship, human worship. No, that one is
wrong.
We find someone who prospers by the
dignity of kingdom integrity and we say,
"Oh, you know what? These guys, they are
just funny. I'm sure God just showed
them a special grace." Special grace?
Are you joking? You find a man having
influence over people like our fathers
in the Lord. Do you know what it means
for people to love, people, to admire,
people to receive, and to keep listening
for decades? How can that be a mistake?
The reason why only few people truly
succeed is because we don't learn. When
God puts models before us, our we are
wrapped up with our pride and bitterness
and envy and we never learn. But I can
tell you mis results are not mistakes
by the mercies of God. One of the things
that God has raised us to do by his
mercy is in all humility to demonstrate
the possibilities of the kingdom to a
generation. Those who are open and can
learn, a portal is created through that
obedience. They can plunge into it and
step into it. Hallelujah. It's not
something to brag about, but it's also
not something to trivialize that God
grants grace and we buy a property in
billions, no asking for funds, no
manipulation, no instrumental payment at
once. And you are not a thief. You don't
do money laundering. It will take a
foolish person to ignore that
that you are able to help people and
bless people. I made a covenant with God
and I've told you in this ministry for
as long as I am alive, nobody will be
manipulated here for financial gains or
whatever it is.
We grew up in ministry and we saw people
doing it. We were able to edit out of
love the things we saw that we did not
believe. We honor them and pick the ones
that are word compliant and use it to
frame our understanding.
Take away finances. How about souls? How
about souls? Sometimes when I get the
record as they sent to me, the souls
that were saved during the conferences,
I say it was worth the while. Ladies and
gentlemen, I don't mean to sound
arrogant, but please forgive me. I'm
challenging you and the body of Christ.
You have no idea the budget and the
bills for this convention coming. I'm
telling you, if I tell you, you'll be
afraid.
That's the price of integrity, but
that's also the price of preparation.
If you get it, don't trivialize it.
Hallelujah. Don't trivialize it. The
things that we do that we do easily, you
come for a miracle service and you find
people flying up and down, you try it.
Try it. You know the depth of work with
the spirit that produces those results.
No sir. No sir.
Coonia let me tell you this. Learn the
way of honor.
Everyone graced by God should be humble
but don't take humility for granted.
There is sacrifice behind it. I am what
I am. He says by the grace of God. But
this grace was not showered on me.
The Lord told me many years ago, he
says, "If you will let men see me, do
you know what it means to hide behind
the cross, everybody also wants to be a
celebrity. I can design a system for
myself to shine. I'm not a fool. I'm not
a dummy. I can design a system of fame
for myself." But we choose to hide
behind the cross and to let Jesus be
seen. Don't trivialize it.
Hallelujah. Praise the name of the Lord.
You must obtain grace to make quality
proestiny choices. Quality proestiny
choices. Trust in the Lord with all your
heart is a choice. Lean on unto your own
understanding is a choice. In all your
ways acknowledge him is a choice. The
result he shall direct your path. Be not
wise in your own eyes. Is a choice. Fear
the Lord and turn away from evil. It's a
choice. I set before you life and death
is a choice. This book of the law shall
not depart from out of your mouth. It's
a choice, sir. It's a choice. A diligent
hand, it's a choice. A lazy hand, it's a
choice. Giving excuses, it's a choice.
Killing every excuse is a choice.
Becoming an exceptional worshipper, it's
a choice. Becoming an anointed man of
God, it's a choice. Becoming a
cuttingedge businessman, it's a choice.
Are we together? Becoming an exceptional
mother who your children will bless God
that you are their mother, it's a
choice. It's not a desire. Becoming an
exceptional father that raises a winning
kingdom family is a choice, sir. Ending
poverty is a choice. Breaking
generational causes is a choice.
Stepping into the blessing is a choice.
Influence is a choice. Redefining the
narratives of your life is a choice.
The assignment of the word of God, the
assignment of the ministry of the Holy
Spirit is to guide you towards making
superior choices. Tonight's teaching is
hard, but it's for your profiting. My
brothers and my sisters, listen to me.
God is provoking us. I want you as
you're standing now, I'm going to just
run. I I will end by doing a recap. One
time when I taught on I think choose
life, I gave you seven major choices. I
will still give you those choices as we
wrap up. I will remind you. I told you
there are major choices in life and
there are minor choices. All of them are
important but not equally important.
My prayer is that at the end of this
discussion tonight, someone will take
advantage of the victory that is in
Christ and use your will through the
power of choices. Come into partnership
with what Christ has done and redefine a
great destiny. Look at me. You can
choose after this service to make up
your mind that friends that are about to
destroy my life, I love them, but I have
to wave them goodbye. It's a choice.
Will you feel lonely afterwards? Yes.
But it's a choice. You are going to make
up your mind that no day will pass
without me praying. It's a choice. The
grace is and by the mercies of God, I'm
praying for you. If you don't choose
anything right in life, please take
these seven destiny defining decisions.
Take them seriously. Number one, the
decision to be spiritually vibrant
to make exceptional spiritual progress
with your life. Please everybody write
that down. That's the first decision
everybody must make. You want to
manifest a life of victory,
a life that is designed by choice,
manifesting limitless possibilities. The
first key is a decision
to be spiritually vibrant to make
exceptional spiritual progress. What
does that mean? Make up your mind that
you will know the Lord. You will love
him and you will serve him all the days
of your life. I've made up my mind
to go God's way the rest of my life.
I've made up my mind to go God's way the
rest of my life.
>> I'll sing it one more time. I've made up
my mind to go God's way the rest of my
life.
I've made up my mind.
>> Not being a Christian and doing
masquerade. Made up my mind to go God's
way the rest of my life. Are we
together? Not being born again and
having one stone from somewhere in your
house. One small shrine say it doesn't
hurt. He was given all of us in our
family. I've made up my mind to go God's
way. Not not not being born again and
tying something around because it was
prayed upon and was given to you. I
don't care what it is called. I'm not
condemning you. But the first decision
you can make, listen. And this decision
has an effect on you and your children
and your children's children.
They entered a covenant to serve the
Lord with their whole heart. The Bible
says they rejoiced. The whole of Judah
rejoiced at it that they made up their
minds that anyone who did not serve the
Lord so will be stoned to death, him and
his family. And the Bible says as they
made that covenant, God gave them rest
round about.
For as long as Uzziah sought the Lord,
he said God made him to prosper.
I have no other God
but you.
You have done what no man can do.
[Music]
You will do what?
>> Hallelujah. Praise God. I'm showing you
the implication.
If it's not in your presence,
if it's not by your hand,
[Music]
if it's not by your spirit,
don't let me have it.
for everything I need.
If it's not in your presence,
[Music]
if it's not from your hand, no matter
what it is in this life, if it's not by
your spirit,
please don't let me have it.
for everything I need in you.
>> If it's not in your presence, listen to
what I'm saying.
If it's not from your hands,
[Music]
and if it's not by your spirit,
don't let me have it.
Everything I need is to.
>> If that money is not from your presence,
if it's not by your hand, if it's not
engineered by your spirit, I'm not
interested. I'm showing you what it
means to love Jesus. It's not just to
confess it. No.
Loving Jesus comes with an implication
of the willingness to die to anything
and any other influence.
For everything I need is in you.
I found out in my little life that what
God does not give a man, you cannot have
it. I'm telling you truly everything I
need is in you.
The joy that I need,
the peace that I have,
everything I need is in you.
Let me tell you this, ladies and
gentlemen.
There are many people looking for joy
and peace elsewhere, fratonizing with
all kinds of foreign, strange, demonic,
and familiar spirits. With all due
respect, there are men and women of God
who dapple into all kinds of things in
search for power, in search for fame. I
tell you this, ladies and gentlemen,
what God will not give you, you can't
get it anywhere. And if the devil there
lies to you, he will only be baiting you
for your destruction.
God is enough for me. God is enough for
me.
Christ alone,
cornerstone,
the weak made strong
in the father's love
through the helping.
He is Lord.
Lord of just let me sing it once. I'm
ministering to your spirit.
Christ the Lord,
cornerstone,
the weak made strong in the Savior's
love
through the storm.
He is Lord.
Lord,
we used to sing this song years ago. I
pledge aliance to
the lamb with all my heart
with all I am
to wonder.
>> Some of you don't know these songs.
>> I pledge
alce
to the lamb.
>> Hallelujah.
The decision to be spiritually serious.
The decision to be spiritually vibrant.
Your prayer life, your love for Jesus,
your love for his house, your love for
the things of God, your commitment to
serving his purpose is number two. What
is the second destiny defining decision
that anyone intending to birth and
manifest victory must pursue? The
decision to contend for a superior
belief system. Ah,
the decision to contend for a superior
belief system. A belief system greater
than the foundation you came from. A
belief system greater than your
immediate environment. I told you a
loser's mentality,
a loser's belief system cannot make a
winner's decision. Don't forget that.
We make decisions to reflect our
understanding, our mindset, our beliefs,
our ideologies.
You must make up your mind that the
second decision will be to contend for
superior transformation, a superior
belief system.
The way you think, the way you talk must
be upgraded. The way you think. Don't
say I'm a Euroba person. You are Euroba
by natural descent. I understand. You
are Ebo. You are housea. You are
plateau. Kaduna, American, Caribbean,
Chinese. And that's wonderful. There's a
place for honor of culture and
foundation. But in terms of mindset, you
must edit principles and practices that
are inconsistent.
You must unashamedly,
unapologetically
divorce any way of thinking whether it
came from culture, whether it came from
background. If it's not consistent with
the word of God and does not produce a
victorious life nor bring glory to the
Lord, dump it. Dump it.
Dump it. Where I come from, when women
offend you, you may say we beat them.
Dump it. It's not found in the word of
God.
where I come. If I'm angry, I don't cook
for my husband. Dump it. It's not found
in the word. No sir. No sir. No sir.
Superior belief system.
You can change your clothes but if the
same mindset wearing the clothes your
result will be the same. Are we
together? You can change cream. You can
change whatever. You can even change
your voice but if it's the same mindset
you will get the same outcome. You can
change physical location and nothing is
intrinsically wrong with that but if
your mindset does not change believe me
coonia your life will remain stunted.
Contend for a superior belief system.
Some of you are truly born again but my
goodness your mindset betrays you. When
we are reading scriptures, singing
songs, psalms, hymn, spiritual songs,
you look like a Christian, but upon
engaging you in conversation,
you speak like one who has not met Jesus
Christ. It must change. Three,
what is the third destiny defining
decision you must make from this
teaching? The decision to discover and
fulfill your assignment.
Hebrews 10:7, "Lo, I come in the volume
of the book as it is written of me to do
your will, oh God." The decision to
discover and to fulfill your assignment.
You must answer that question. Why? Why
am I here?
Your assignment is your contribution to
kingdom come. Your assignment is
your contribution to the advancement of
the kingdom of God.
You must find it and you must leave it.
And let me tell you this, ladies and
gentlemen, the easiest way I know to
evolve into your call is to serve in the
house of God.
Four,
the decision to be healthy and
physically strong. It's a
destinydefining decision.
the decision to be healthy and
physically strong. I think I've said it
here in Coonia that usually at the end
of the year I do my retreats and during
my retreats I take inventory of my life
across many indices. One of them being
my health and my physical well-being and
I remember for three years in a row not
that I was particularly sick but my
health was the worst performing index of
all the indices in my life. spiritual
vibrancy, mindset, but health. And I
made up my mind. I said, you know what?
I refuse to die.
Decisions. But that decision would not
just end there. You also have to start
removing death from your port. You don't
just say, "I refuse to die." And eat
death. You will die.
Are we together? Praise the name of the
Lord.
I have a very sweet tooth. I buried it.
I don't know if it's fully buried now,
but at least I tried burying it. I
buried it. I think it has it has died
significantly. Has died. Maybe not
completely died, but it has died. I am
sure of that. A part of it will not
resurrect again.
Health.
So when you say I shall not die, but
live and declare, make sure you
understand it's not just a confession.
It's a responsibility.
Are we together? Yes.
Responsibility.
Laziness kills.
Overworking kills too.
This is where you need to pray for some
of us. As I'm saying it now, I'm feeling
guilty. The message is also you see how
God is speaking to everyone including
me.
Are we together? Praise the name of the
Lord.
Please take your health seriously. Do
you know what a doctor told me? I'm not
a medical practitioner, but he said for
every 10 years of your life, the
dynamics of taking care of yourself and
the way your body works changes.
0 to 10,
11 to 20. Then when you start getting
from 20 to 30, 30 to 40, 40 to 50, these
three decades, that's where most of the
sicknesses that kill people around 60
years, that's where it starts from. It
usually starts from the 20s, but they
are careless. Pain in the leg, they're
careless. What pain? I don't care.
Sometime you know disease not they kill
and we are doing all those things, it
keeps building up.
I pray for you in Jesus name. Whatever
it takes in Christ and in righteousness
for you to maintain good health, please
do it in Jesus name.
>> I think the last time I was teaching you
on decisions here, I spoke about a
simple instruction like drinking water
can save your life. I hope you know that
when God starts blessing you, the first
thing to change is the quality of the
water you drink. It's not luxury. You
are living long. I'm telling you, it's
not luxury.
And in Nigeria, we don't do that. to
find out that someone will barely take
one glass of water in a day, but he will
take Coca-Cola with all due respect. He
will take Fanta, he will take all other
beverages. Wonderful in their own
rights. But if whatever you do, if you
ignore water, just know that you are
signing a contract with death. Thank you
for watching this powerful video. I hope
you were blessed. Apostle Jose is really
a blessing to our generation and our
prayer for him is that the Lord will
keep him from falling. We encourage you
to drop your comments on the comment
section. We promise to respond to every
comment you see on the comment section.
We value your response. If you've not
subscribed to our channel, what are you
waiting for? This is a family of God. We
encourage you to subscribe to this
family so that God will bless you. We
also encourage you to share this video
with your family and friends so that
they can be blessed as well. Don't
forget, my name is Mr. Jacob and this is
Priy Nation. We're going to see you on
the next sermon. Bye.
[Music]